# **Umer Syed**

Ottawa, Canada 226 791 5113 · <u>umerdevs@proton.me</u>

Skills				
HTML & CSS				
PHP				
С				
VMWare				
SQL				
MySQL				
NoSQL				
MongoDB				
Bash				
Java				
ReactJS				
NodeJS				
jQuery				
Bootstrap				
Git				
Linux				
Python				
JavaScript				
LUA				
Microsoft Office				

# **Profile**

Full-stack developer with a background in criminology and certifications from various universities. Strong foundation in React and NodeJS and enjoys solving puzzles and challenges. Creative, divergent thinking, and not afraid to challenge the norm. Possesses strong analytical and research skills and capable of managing multiple tasks to meet tight deadlines. Excellent communication skills and attention to detail, contributes to projects and propose solutions effectively. Several years of experience, with 2 years being in the healthcare IT sector.

# **Employment History**

## System Engineer, Carestream Health Canada, Concord, ON

February 2021 — January 2023

- Managed escalated network, operating systems and database issues employing Solaris/Oracle environment
- Troubleshooting ASN and EDI issues and ensuring that errors/problems caused during order submission
- Utilized SQL queries in troubleshooting database issues
- Maintained and Troubleshooting SharePoint sites for Intra-dept notes and client modules kept on file
- Provided support to end users on installation, configuration and project support through managing hardware and software requirements
- Provided clear and concise directions to cross functional departments, documentation, customer correspondence to deliver network and product support
- Provided on site support to technical issues logged in the system
- Provided updates to management as defined in business processes and practices for accounts including detailed month end resolution

#### Certified Specialist, Best Buy, Ottawa, ON

October 2018 — February 2021

- Provided technical support to customers for hardware and software-related issues.
- Implemented advanced analytics and tracking to measure the performance of marketing campaigns
- Made recommendations for products, and services
- Team leader, health and safety team and member of the employee committee

#### **Hobbies**

Co-Founder of MainFrame Gaming:

We host a variety of game servers, with custom LUA scripts to make a more custom and unique gaming experience! A friendly and large gaming community consisting of over 1000 members, 200+ active daily
A friendly and large gaming community consisting of over 1000 members, 200+ active daily

## Languages

Languages		
English		
French		
Urdu		
Hindi		
Punjabi		

#### Head of IT, CanadaCars, Waterloo

September 2017 — September 2018

- Managed the IT department and oversaw the development of new software and websites to enhance the online customer experience.
- Provided technical support to team members and ensured seamless integration of software systems.
- Assured all employees were up to date on the software used for their respective departments
- · Created interactive training modules for health and safety training

#### Parts and Service Advisor, Cambridge Hyundai

June 2015 - January 2017

- Worked as a parts and service advisor and provided technical support to customers for their vehicles.
- Assisted with the sale of parts and services to improve customer satisfaction and increase revenue.
- Created spreadsheets to make for more efficient and accurate inventory and stock counts.

# **Education**

BA Criminology, Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

Full Stack Development with NodeJS Certification, Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

#### **Various Certifications**

- Advanced Google Analytics Google
- · Machine Learning Stanford University
- CS50's Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with Python Harvard University
- CS50's Introduction to Game Development Harvard University

#### **Projects:**

- · Password Generator
- · ReadME Generator
- Team Profile Generator
- Employee Tracker
- Workday Scheduler
- · Weather App
- · Note Taker

#### **Extracurriculars**

- · Volunteer Parking Services Waterloo Masjid
- Juniour Achievement and DECA Volunteer Coordinator
- UW Hackathons